Joshua Zhang

Motivated high school tutor focused on Math, Physics, and Programming subjects. 6+ Years of programming experience, 4+ years of cybersecurity experience, 1 year of research experience. Send me an email for private tutoring options (helping with a class at school or learning a new topic).

EXPERIENCE

Identifying NEOs using Machine Learning

June 2021 - May 2022

Research

- Used Tensorflow to identify 40+ Near Earth Objects (NEOs) within NASA's WISE database.
- Designed and optimized a neural network that subtracts two images to identify moving objects.
- Learned and used image interpolation to fill in missing pixels in images.
- Won 1st place at Alameda Regional Science Fair

COSMOS Quantum Mechanics

July 2022 - August 2022

UC Davis, CA

- Completed a 4 week program involving introductory courses in quantum mechanics and programming in C.
- Worked with a team of five to build a working Scanning Tunneling Microscope to scan the atomic surface of a graphene sample.
- Wrote a computer program to simulate the time evolution of a quantum mechanical system using Spectral Decomposition Theory.
 It could reproduce the special case of a perfect Quantum State
 Transfer discovered 10 years ago.

EDUCATION

Monta Vista High School (Student)

August 2019 – June 2023

GPA: 3.93, SAT: 1550, ACT: 35

 Relevant Courses: AP Calculus BC, AP Physics C, AP Physics 1, AP Computer Science A, APUSH

West Valley College

August 2022 - December 2022

• Relevant Courses: Linear Algebra, Differential Equations

AWARDS

USAPHO Honorable Mention (Qualifier 2x)	2021 & 2022
National Cyber Scholar	2022
PicoCTF Top 40 (2x)	2021 & 2022
CyberPatriot Platinum (2x)	2020 & 2021
Alameda County Science Fair 1st	2022
1st Place Pacific Hackers Asc.	2022
4th Place Mitre Stem CTF	2022
10th Place PBJAR CTF	2021
11th Place RedPwn	2021
(More Unlisted)	

CONTACT

- · Cupertino, CA (Open to Remote)
- · +1-408-888-8361
- · zhy0224@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/joshua-zhang-63 a095236/
- · github.com/Teddygat0r

SKILLS

Languages:

- · HTML
- · CSS
- · Javascript / NodeJS
- · PHP
- · MySQL
- Python
- Java
- · Bash

Cybersecurity:

- Web Exploits (SQLI, XSS, CSRF
- Cryptography
- · Cloud Security

Tools and Frameworks:

- React
- · Vue 3
- Nuxt 3
- TailwindCSS
- Bootstrap
- Django
- · Python (BS4, Numpy, Matplotlib)

OTHER

- Co-founder of Fweefwop, a four year old cybersecurity club.
- · Co-host of FweefwopCTF
- · Strong Problem Solver
- · Fluent in Chinese
- Filmed and edited a variety of short films

